Guide to the Julie Kathryn Franco (I Am Snow Angel) Collection MSS.480
Fales Library and Special Collections
Julie Kathryn Franco I Am Snow Angel Papers
2014-2016
Fales Library and Special Collections
Franco, Julie Kathryn
I Am Snow Angel
MSS.480
7.08 Gigabytes in 65 computer files and 1 archived website.
4.9 Gigabytes in 5 video files.
1.64 Gigabytes in 41 audio files.
46.71 kilobytes in 1 spreadsheet.
24.95 Megabytes in 18 graphic files.
141.6 Megabytes in 1 archived website.
The Julie Kathryn Franco I am Snow Angel Papers is composed of the works of music artist Julie Kathryn Franco between 2014-2016 under her performance alias I Am Snow Angel, which she uses to produce electronica music. The collection includes sound recordings from 5 EPs, 1 full-length album, 6 singles and 5 music videos, all written and performed by I Am Snow Angel. It also includes the website iamsnowangel.com, which includes a brief biography of the artist, performance videos, audio recordings, and articles featuring Julie Kathryn Franco and her work as I Am Snow Angel.
Scope and Contents
The Julie Kathryn Franco I Am Snow Angel Papers documents the work of female music artist Julie Kathryn Franco under her performance alias I Am Snow Angel between 2014-2016. The collection contains 41 sound recordings and 5 video recordings made by Franco; an archived copy of iamsnowangel.com, the website owned and operated by Franco; 18 image files of album art; and one spreadsheet created by Franco with information about each recording. The website includes a brief biography of the artist, performance videos, audio recordings, and articles featuring Franco and her work as I Am Snow Angel. The image files are digital copies of the artwork included with her albums, the creator(s) of which are unknown. These files are arranged with the sound recordings for the relevant albums. The spreadsheet includes information about the recordings, including format, title, and release information.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged according to the format of the material, then alphabetically by title.
Biographical Note
Julie Kathryn Franco is a female music artist who grew up in Lake Placid, New York and currently lives in New York City. She was a social worker for several years before she began recording her music. She was raised performing music, and has experimented with several styles in her recording career. She put out her first Americana Noir EP, "Broken Love", in 2012 under the name Julie Kathryn, followed by her first full-length album, "Black Trees", in 2013. In 2014, she embarked on a new musical project under the name I Am Snow Angel to explore self-produced electronica.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Julie Kathryn Franco, September 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2017.021.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archiveit.org/organizations/567
Take-down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information. If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials. If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to fales.library@nyu.edu. Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Custodial History
Websites are selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
Conditions Governing Access
Sound and video recordings are available for streaming with password authentification from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval from the NYU Libraries based on a 2016 agreement with the donor.
Composition (Music) -- 21st century.; Video recordings.; Electronic music.; Women musicians -- United States.; Music -- New York (State) -- New York.; Sound recordings.
- Archived Website, 2014-ongoing; cuid5812 (Box Electronic records, E-records https://wayback.archive-it.org/4049/*/http://www.iamsnowangel.com)
- I Am Snow Angel Media -- Spreadsheet, 2016; cuid5811 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_1)
- Sound Recordings -- EP -- Desert, 2016; cuid5813 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_7)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Sound recordings are available for streaming with password authentification from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval from the NYU Libraries based on a 2016 agreement with the donor.
- Sound Recordings -- EP -- Falling In Love (The Remixes), 2014; cuid5814 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_8)
- Sound Recordings -- EP -- I Am Snow Angel, 2014; cuid5815 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_9)
- Sound Recordings -- EP -- Keep You Out- Remix, 2016; cuid5816 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_10)
- Sound Recordings -- EP -- Walking On Wires, 2015; cuid5817 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_11)
- Sound Recordings -- Full-Length Album -- Crocodile, 2014; cuid5818 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_12)
- Sound Recordings -- Single -- Crocodile, 2014; cuid5819 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_13)
- Sound Recordings -- Single -- Falling, 2016; cuid5820 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_14)
- Sound Recordings -- Single -- Falling In Love (feat. John Carlson), 2014; cuid5821 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_15)
- Sound Recordings -- Single -- Fever, 2016; cuid5822 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_16)
- Sound Recordings -- Single -- Keep You Out, 2015; cuid5823 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_17)
- Sound Recordings -- Single -- Losing Face, 2015; cuid5824 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_18)
- Video Recordings -- "Come With Me", 2014; cuid5825 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_2)
  Video recordings are available for streaming with password authentification from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval from the NYU Libraries based on a 2016 agreement with the donor.
- Video Recordings -- "Crocodile", 2014; cuid5826 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_4)
- Video Recordings -- "Desert (Live)", 2016; cuid5827 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_3)
- Video Recordings -- "Losing Face", 2016; cuid5828 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_480_ER_5)
- Video Recordings -- "Losing Face (Live)", 2015; cuid5829 (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS-480_ER_6)